there is much to be done this time of
year
as the cold sets in for me there is snow
to be shoveled
my finicky furnace has needed to be
fixed twice this year
frost resistant pipes to be checked and
a multitude of other little
tasks preparing my home for the winter
season can be quite time consuming
but i reward myself by extending winter
preparations to inside my home
as well seeing it as getting my little
burrow
ready for a period of hibernation
[Music]
as you may already know i try my best to
buy everything i can
either second hand or make it myself
it has been the best decision i made for
my finances
and for my creativity most of the
furniture you see in my home is
secondhand
sometimes needing only a bit of
sandpaper and new coat of paint
the same goes for my clothing if i
cannot find exactly what i'm looking for
i try to get creative with what i
already have
for example recently i wanted to add
some color to one of my
walls wallpapers are typically too
expensive for my budget
so when i came across some cheap vintage
wallpaper at a thrift shop
i took advantage of it despite it being
a bit
worn and frayed
[Music]
do
decorating my home for wintertime is
always exciting
since i know i'll be spending much more
time indoors
a very wise badger once said
no animal according to the rules of
animal etiquette
is ever expected to do anything
strenuous or heroic or even moderately
active during the off season
of winter this wise saying comes from a
character from the beloved children's
book
the wind and the willows i think that
while i still have to work
quite a bit during the winter i like to
think this way about the time i do spend
at home
it is time to enjoy little moments of
comfort
finish chores around the home and create
a space that inspires creativity
[Music]
so
you may be surprised to know that i am
someone who is easily distracted and
forgetful
it has been a struggle for much of my
life and at times it still is
this part of my person is one of the
reasons that i'm attracted to tasks that
require concentration
and slowness when i can put all my focus
on one thing
worries and thoughts take a backseat and
i'm only there
now absorbed totally in a single thing
a seasonal craft i've been meaning to do
is make a cinnamon broom
it is a popular item i've always seen
available in stores during autumn
i decided to make my own and decorated
the brush after soaking it in cinnamon
oil
the smell is absolutely magical and it
makes me anticipate the holidays
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
in the story from the wind and the
willows there is a sweet character named
mole who desperately misses his home
after going on an adventure
while he enjoys his exciting life above
ground traipsing through the fields and
forests with his friends rat badger and
mr toad
his heart aches for the feeling of
coming home to a place that is familiar
full of coziness and simple welcomes i
hope you can create that feeling as well
this season
be it cold or warm wherever you are
i also hope you enjoyed this very simple
day at the cottage
and i will see you next week with some
festive preparations for the holidays
have a lovely day or night
[Music]
you